# Anthony Castiglione

(708) 878-1803 • anthony.castiglione@gmail.com

# Lead Software Engineer

I am an experienced technical leader with a primary focus on quality and mentorship. Currently focused on Ruby and its associated ecosystem. Through my skills in software design and testing, I aim to produce functional, maintainable software that meets business needs, and I strive to teach others how to do the same.

My ideal next role includes interesting technical problems, opportunities to mentor and teach, and the possibility to give back to the community through open source contributions. Aligning with a highly collaborative team to achieve the needs of the business is my goal for future endeavors.

# Experience

BigCommerce Austin, TX

Lead Software Developer

Jan 2022 - Nov 2024

- $-\,$  Technical lead for 9 ICs on the Billing Platform team
- Directed and assisted several developers on multiple Rails version upgrades  $(5.2 \rightarrow 6.0 \rightarrow 6.1)$
- Upgraded Ruby  $2.7 \rightarrow 3.0 \rightarrow 3.1$  on the main legacy codebase with a near-zero error rate
- Contributed features and bugfixes for engineering-wide internal Ruby gems
- Supported Rails apps and Ruby microservices with multiple external vendor APIs (Zuora, eNom, Google Workspace)
- Led decomissioning of unused/abandoned external integrations and services
- Acted as a technical mentor for junior and mid-level developers
- Joined the Data Acceleration Team (DAT), working in Go/Ruby development tooling codebases and Terraform to provision internal developer development environments (a scaled down version of the entire platform)
- Maintained legacy cloud-based development environment tooling and infrastructure (Rails, GCP) used by all
  engineers to provision and interact with their cloud-based development environment
- Primary point-of-contact for development environment issues/requests for engineers company-wide
- Spearheaded DAT effort to modernize legacy Ruby-based command line interface to our internal cloud-based development environment tooling with a purpose-built Go command line interface

UrbanBound Chicago, IL

Lead Engineer

Mar 2021 - Nov 2021

- Primarly focused on upgrading the legacy Rails app from  $4.2 \rightarrow 5.0$ , completing the upgrade with a near-zero error rate
- Upgraded application infrastructure, updating or replacing versions of many core libraries that were out of date (Pow, Active Admin, Puma, Selenium/Capybara)
- Created and updated components in a React front-end
- Acted as a technical mentor for junior and mid-level developers

# Praetorian Security Staff Software Developer

Austin, TX

Oct 2020 - Jan 2021

- Java development on a highly factored service based application architecture
- Added ability to track and audit client data ingestion across multiple services

# **Anthony Castiglione**

(708) 878-1803 • anthony.castiglione@gmail.com

## Kenna Security (acquired by Cisco)

Chicago, IL

Lead Software Developer

Feb 2016 - Oct 2020

- Responsible for new feature development on a Ruby/Rails-based SaaS product in the security space in an individual role as well as with a small team
- Instrumental in developing an asynchronous data ingestion pipeline for client data capable of parsing and persisting hundreds of millions of records daily
- Extensively mentored developers at all skill levels on technical and career related matters
- Led a team of 3-5 developers working on new feature development, platform maintenance, and on-call duties
- Interfaced with Operations, Site Reliability, and Product Management teams on cross-team collaboration, primarily focused on project planning and providing direction for Product/Project Management around technical roadmap planning at a company level

#### Yello (formerly Recsolu)

Chicago, IL

Jun 2015 - Feb 2016

Senior Software Developer

- Responsible for new feature development on a Rails-based SaaS product
- Mentored several junior developers on best practices for coding and testing

#### DialogTech (formerly Ifbyphone)

Chicago, IL

Senior Software Developer

Oct 2013 - June 2015

- Implemented a Ruby back-end for VOIP based phone call processing based on the Adhearsion framework
- Maintained and developed a redundant cluster of call processing software including servers running Kamailio,
   Adhearsion, Asterisk, and Lumenvox ASR
- Identified production critical memory leak in a combination of gems and implemented an upgrade plan, improving expected uptime from days to months

#### Backstop Solutions Group, LLC

Chicago, IL

Software Developer & System Operations

Aug 2007 - Oct 2013

- Maintained and developed a web-based client relation management and accounting application written in Java on a JBoss/Hibernate platform
- Assisted production support team with critical system bugs and queries as an on-call technical lead, on a rotating schedule
- Ruby/Rails work includes improving cross-product backend import of large datasets, new feature development,
   maintenance of legacy code and creation of unit and Cucumber tests via Test-Driven Development including major feature addition, overall platform stability, performance improvements, bug fixes, and new issue triage

## Education

**DePaul University** 

Chicago, IL

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Jun 2005 to Nov 2007

University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

Urbana-Champaign, IL

Course of Study: Computer Science

Sep 2003 to Dec 2004

## Core Technical Skills

#### Languages & Tools

AJAX, AWS, Bash, CircleCI, Elasticsearch, GCP, Git, Linux, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Puma,

RSpec, Rbenv, React, Redis, Resque, Ruby (On Rails), SQL, Sikekiq, Vim

## Limited Experience

Ansible, Common Lisp, CSS, Docker, Go, Java, Javascript/Typescript, Perl, Python/Django, IATFX,

Terraform/Terragrunt, Puppet